<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alex Tran on Quang-Anh Ngo Tran</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Alex Tran on Quang-Anh Ngo Tran</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 18:12:11 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recommended Books</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/books/</guid><description>Here are some of the books I have read and recommend. The genre divide is not entirely accurate and one book can fall into multiple categories.
Textbooks Psychology of Prejudice and Discrimination - Mary E. Kite, Bernard E. Whitley, Jr., Lisa S. Wagner [view here]
The Making of Asian America: A History - Erika Lee [view here]
The Asian American Achievement Paradox - Jennifer Lee, Min Zhou [view here]
Novels On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous - Ocean Vuong [view here]</description></item><item><title>Petals</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/petalshide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/petalshide/</guid><description>[Drawing by me]
One petal
You were so young
And so was I.
We locked arms
Exchanging a love shot
Sealing our fates.
Sleepless nights
He loves me.
Two petals
Our fates ever so twisted
For it was not arms that were locked
But the spiral of confidence and egos
That brought us both down.
In a capitalistic business
Cloaked as academic institution,
You became a pawn,
I, a hero.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/about/</guid><description>Introduction I am a second-year graduate student in Social Psychology at Indiana University Bloomington from Vietnam, advised by Dr. Amanda Diekman. I am particularly interested in stereotyping, bias, prejudice, intersectionality, and interminority coalition.
Hobby I love reading, dancing, creative writing, and playing League of Legends and Teamfight Tactics in my free time.</description></item><item><title>Awards &amp; Honors</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/awards/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/awards/</guid><description>Citizenship Award in Psychological and Brain Sciences Awarded by the department for outstanding contributions to the Psychological and Brain Sciences department through exemplary leadership, service, and achievement.
Phil R. Miller Prize in Psychology Established in memory of Lt. Phil R. Miller &amp;lsquo;41, who lost his life in the service of his country in World War II, and awarded to a junior or senior psychology major demonstrating unusual interest in and capacity for work in psychology.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/cv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/cv/</guid><description>Here you can find my CV.</description></item><item><title>mediacover</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/mediacover/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/mediacover/</guid><description>Here you can find media coverages of my and my colleagues&amp;rsquo; work.
Blogs [Gender, race, and power: Unpacking the dynamics of workplace perceptions]</description></item><item><title>On Friendship</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/onfriendshiphide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/onfriendshiphide/</guid><description>The first time I met Josh was during Orientation Week for International Students at Colgate University, a small elite privileged liberal arts institution in upstate New York. The breezes of fall swept my attention away at every minute, but Josh kept my attention back on the ground. I was a magnet and so was he. Everyone was circling around him, so I chose to avoid him. In the stuffed cubical room, we were polar opposites.</description></item><item><title>On Teaching and Gardening</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/onteachingandgardening/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/blogs/onteachingandgardening/</guid><description>[Drawing by me, inspired by Youtuber @EveryTuesday]
“How do I even begin teaching students with amazingly diverse worldviews and rich perspectives without enforcing my own on them?” This was my dilemma as I began my first teaching position. An opening to the conundrum presented itself when I mentored my first undergraduate senior. Although we had different research interests at the time, we both realized that Social Psychology was our shared way of understanding the experiences of marginalized groups and our own experiences.</description></item><item><title>R With Alex</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/rwithalex/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/rwithalex/</guid><description>R With Alex With the help and feedback of a lot of friends and colleagues, I have written tutorials on how to use R for data analysis, for beginners with zero experience with any coding languages. I hope this serves as a good resource for you.
You can find the blog here.
Have fun learning and feel free to share it with anyone who you think would benefit from it. These tutorials are definitely works in progress.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/research/</guid><description>Here you can find my publications and posters/talks sorted chronologically.
Publications Diekman, A. B., Joshi, M. P., White, A. D., Tran, Q. A. N., &amp;amp; Seth, J. (2024). Purpose reflection benefits minoritized students’ motivation and well-being in STEM. Scientific Reports, 14(1), 466. [view here]
Tran, Q.-A. N., Cooley, E., Lisnek, J. A., Brown-Iannuzzi, J. L., &amp;amp; Cipolli, W. (2023). Racialized Sexism: Nonverbal Displays of Power in Workplace Settings are Evaluated as More Masculine When Displayed by White (vs.</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 18:12:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://quanganhtranngo.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>Graduate Teaching Assistant Spring 2024 Statistical Techniques, Indiana University Bloomington
Fall 2023 Social Neuroscience, Indiana University Bloomington
Summer 2023 Introduction to R Statistical Environment, University of Michigan Ann Arbor
Spring 2022 Laboratory In Social Psychology, Indiana University Bloomington
Fall 2022 Social Psychology and the Law, Indiana University Bloomington
Professional Services and Community Outreach 2023 Workshop Leader, Managing the STEM Classroom, Indiana University’s Center for Innovative Teaching and Learning
2022-now Book Club Leader, Indiana University&amp;rsquo;s Asian Cultural Center</description></item></channel></rss>